<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Soliprem</title>
		<link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Soliprem</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>2024</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 03:28:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>La figura di Shostakovich come un Sisifo moderno</title>
			<link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/shostakovich_sisifo/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 03:28:00 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/shostakovich_sisifo/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[%!s(<nil>)]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduzione">Introduzione</h2>
<p>Nelle scienze politiche, esiste una visione delle interazioni sociali
che presenta quest&rsquo;ultime come una serie di &lsquo;giochi&rsquo;. In questi, ci sono
tre possibili azioni che un partecipante messo in condizione di disagio
da un&rsquo;azione o situazione può scegliere di prendere: &lsquo;Voice&rsquo;, &lsquo;Loyalty&rsquo;,
o &lsquo;Exit&rsquo;. Mentre Loyalty ed Exit sono molto autoesplicativi
(corrispondono infatti all&rsquo;adattarsi per convivere con la situazione, o
uscirne interamente), voice è più interessante. Voice prevede infatti la
possibilità di <strong>protestare</strong>, e quindi manifestare il proprio fastidio,
nella speranza di ottenere un cambiamento favorevole.<br>
Uno degli elementi fondamentali del mito di Sisifo, nell&rsquo;interpretazione
assurdista, è la perseveranza vista come manifestazione della Protesta.
Si attribuisce quindi in quest&rsquo;ottica un valore intrinseco all&rsquo;atto di
protesta verso una condizione fondamentalmente assurda che va aldilà
della possibilità di una ricompensa, come nel caso della teoria dei
giochi (in cui il valore netto dell&rsquo;attività &lsquo;Voice&quot; è di fatto negativo
se non ci osno risultati tangibili).<br>
Dimitri Shostakovich era un compositore Sovietico durante la seconda
guerra mondiale e la guerra fredda. La sua carriera, nata nel periodo
fiorente delle avanguardie, passa attraverso il restringimento della
censura di stato, per arrivare infine nel pieno regime totalitario
stalinista, e le regole ferree che vengono introdotte sull&rsquo;arte e
l&rsquo;espressione personale. In questa fase della sua carriera, Dimitri
Shostakovich dimostra il suo spirito Sisifico nel sopportare la
condizione di estrema restrizione priva di speranza di uscita attraverso
una protesta muta di parole, ma certamente non di suono.</p>
<h2 id="shostakovich-un-giovane-impavido">Shostakovich, un giovane impavido</h2>
<p>Inizialmente, Shostakovich segue il percorso delle avanguardie ancora
nel periodo iniziale della censura Stalinista. Questo si può notare nel
carattere quasi Ligetiano delle armonie nelle sue prime sinfonie, ed
opere. Imparerà presto, però, che sarebbe stato necessario trovare un
sano equilibrio fra scrivere musica che piacesse a lui, e musica che
piacesse a Stalin. Infatti, durante un&rsquo;esecuzione di &lsquo;Lady Machbet&quot; alla
quale stava assistendo Stalin in persona, quest&rsquo;ultimo esce furibondo e
disgustato. Il giorno dopo, Shostakovich trova una &lsquo;recensione molto
negativa&quot; sul giornale. Questa si conclude, a seguito di grosse critiche
sul carattere astratto, amelodico, e sgraziato della sua opera, con la
frase &lsquo;questo è un gioco che potrebbe concludersi molto male&rsquo;. Vista la
velata minaccia da parte del Partito, Shostakovich inizia ad essere più
sottile nell&rsquo;espressione dei propri interessi musicali devianti. Da qui
in poi, però, inizia il suo rapporto altalenante con lo stato. Questi
sono stati il primo periodo di approvazione, ed il primo periodo di
disapprovazione da parte del suo governo, ma on saranno gli ultimi.</p>
<h2 id="shostakovich-inizia-a-scontare-la-sua-pena">Shostakovich inizia a scontare la sua pena</h2>
<p>A seguito di Lady Machbet, le opere orchestrali di Shostakovich si fanno
più sottili. maschera le critiche al partito come critiche
all&rsquo;occidente, oppure nasconde i suoi esperimenti musicali, come fa ne
&ldquo;l&rsquo;età dell&rsquo;oro&rdquo; sostenendo di mettere a confronto &ldquo;la degeneratezza&rdquo;
dell&rsquo;occidente con &ldquo;il vigore sportivo&rdquo; dell&rsquo;unione sovietica. È chiaro
analizzando l&rsquo;opera quale delle due fazioni avesse gli elementi musicali
più interessanti, tuttavia.<br>
Un caso emblematico di questo periodo è la Quinta. Pubblicata
accompagnata da una nota che la descriveva come &ldquo;la risposta creativa di
un artista sovietico ad una critica giustificata&rdquo;, è considerata un
successo dal partito, che la sente in linea con l&rsquo;estetica sovietica, ma
anche dal pubblico, che la percepisce come un grido di rabbia e dolore
in risposta alla censura.<br>
Un caso analogo è la Settima, scritta durante l&rsquo;assedio di Leningrado da
parte dei nazisti. La sinfonia viene ricevuta dal partito con
sufficiente calore da fare escogitare all&rsquo;esercito nazista un piano per
interromperne la prima. Il partito la vede come una celebrazione delle
vittorie militari dell&rsquo;unione, ed una critica sferrata al regime
nazista. Shostakovich rileva che non si tratta di una critica
indirizzata solo ai nazisti ma &lsquo;anche al nostro sistema&rsquo;, o meglio, a
tutti i totalitarismi.</p>
<h3 id="la-musica-da-camera">La musica da camera</h3>
<p>Mentre la musica orchestrale era sotto strettissimo scrutinio, nello
scrivere musica da camera, Shostakovich poteva sentirsi più libero. È
qui che si vedono le sperimentazioni più grandi, e che si snte la voce
cruda e ruvida del compositore. È qui che, nel piccolo della musica da
camera, Shostakovich Protesta le ingiustizie che percepisce nel mondo.
nel 1944, quando iniziano a sentirsi voci dell&rsquo;Olocausto che stava
avvenendo in Germania; Shostakovich nello stesso periodo perde un caro
amico, che per caso o per destino è ebreo. L&rsquo;autore quindi, già solito
includere passaggi in Frigia dominante, (in Yiddish, <em>Freygish</em>.
Figura 1) compone un trio di pianoforte d&rsquo;archi in
cui essa compare straziata, portata all&rsquo;estremo del grottesco. Questa,
rivela a corrispondenti, è una critica non solo all&rsquo;antisemitismo della
Geramania nazista, ma anche all&rsquo;antisemitismo in Russia, che sopprime
anch&rsquo;essa la cultura ebraica in questo periodo storico.</p>
<p><img src="./ahava-rabbah.jpg" alt="yiddish">
<em>Figura 1. scala frigia dominante</em></p>
<p>Dichiarazioni di questo tipo non sono insolite per
Shostakovich. Soprattutto nella musica da camera, non è insolito che
riversi una parte delle sue sofferenze nella forma di una composizione.
Questo è chiaramente visibile in composizioni come l&rsquo;ottavo quartetto
d&rsquo;archi, pensato da molti essere scritto inizialmente come una lettera
di suicidio.<br>
Questo viene detto perchè all&rsquo;interno del quartetto si trovano
riferimenti a tutti i suoi temi più grandi, perchè una delle &ldquo;idee&rdquo;
principali è la sua firma (che usa frequentemente nelle sue
composizioni, ma non in questa quantità. Figura 2). In
questa composizione ritorna il tema straziato del matrimonio ebraico,
vengono ripresi temi dalle sue opere sinfoniche, da Lady Machbet, e dei
suoi quartetti precedenti, ed idee da varie sue composizioni.\</p>
<p><img src="./dsch.jpg" alt="imd">
<em>Figura 2. Il tema <strong>D</strong>imitri <strong>S</strong>hostakovi<strong>CH</strong> (in notazione tedesca), firma di Shostakovich che inserisce in molte composizioni</em></p>
<p>Personalmente, sono dell&rsquo;idea che il quartetto d&rsquo;archi non sia
semplicemente una lettera di suicidio, ma una lettera di salvezza: un
grande atto di Ribellione che riassuma quella che ha intessuto nelle sue
composizioni nell&rsquo;arco della sua vita, che in modo sisifico lo riporta
dall&rsquo;orlo del baratro in cui si trovava, pronto a ripartire.</p>
<h2 id="magnum-opus">Magnum Opus</h2>
<p>La Nona sinfonia. Il nome da solo è già evocativo: la Nona di Behetoven,
la Nona di Bruckner, la Nona di Mahler. Stalin, conoscendo bene il
potere della Nona, ed avendo recentemente vinto una guerra molto
importante (l&rsquo;anno è il 1945), nota che Shostakovich ha al momento
scritto solamente 8 sinfonie. Essendosi Shostakovich tenuto nelle grazie
del partito per qualche tempo, decide di commissionare la sua Nona
sinfonia in onore della parata militare in piazza Rossa, a Mosca, che
celebra la vittoria sovietica sul regime nazista.<br>
Shostakovich nota l&rsquo;occasione per compere il singolo più grande atto di
ribellione della sua carriera, e spingere per un&rsquo;altra volta il suo
macigno finto in cima. Per assicurarsi che passi la censura,
Shostakovich scrive la sinfonia in Mi bemolle maggiore. La tonalità
dell&rsquo; <em>Eroica</em> di Behetoven. Questo viene immediatamente minato da un
accordo di sol bemolle già alla quarta battuta, ma probabilmente la
tonalità è stata sufficiente a non farlo notare.<br>
Quello che consegna Shostakovich è un&rsquo;opera leggera, spensierata,
scherzosa. Già nell&rsquo;introduzione il tema degli archi ed il gioco
d&rsquo;intreccio fra i fiati suggerisce un&rsquo;opera scritta come sottofondo ad
una commedia. Questo è enfatizzato ulteriormente all&rsquo;ingresso del
trombone, che suggerisce l&rsquo;inizio di una fanfara maestosa con una
cadenza che sembra essere perfetta, ma che lascia lo spazio
immeddiatamente ad una risposta giocosa da parte dell&rsquo;ottavino. Lo
spirito grottesco viene solo aumentato dalla scelta di introdurre un
ritornello alla fine dell&rsquo;introduzione. Questo è un richiamo alle prime
sinfonie di Haydn, una pratica assolutamente anacronistica per una Nona
moderna. La sinfonia raggiunge l&rsquo;apice del grottesco nel momento in cui
il <em>motif</em> del trombone viene ripetuto per 5 volte fuori posto, come se
il trombone avesse fretta e partisse troppo presto. Questa è una poco
sottile presa in giro dell&rsquo;entusiasmo degli amanti del partito che
dimostrano nel voler essere sempre i primi a dichiarare il loro supporto
al partito, e dà un tono grottesco e francamente ridicolo all&rsquo;intero
primo movimento.<br>
Il tono giocoso, scherzoso, ed ovviamente grottesco della sinfonia non
passa inosservato da Stalin che, in seguito all&rsquo;esibizione, procede a
dare Shostakovich un richiamo ufficiale insieme a Prokofiev e
Kachaturian nel 1948. Viene dichiarato un &rsquo;nemico del popolo&quot; e gli
vengono tolte le sue cattedre. Sarà solo dopo la morte di Stalin che
riuscirà ad uscire da questo stato di isolamento.</p>
<h2 id="il-mito-di-shostakovich">Il mito di Shostakovich</h2>
<p>Riprendendo l&rsquo;inizio de &lsquo;Il mito di Sisifo&quot; di Camus, l&rsquo;unica questione
filosofica degna di considerazione è il suicidio.<br>
Shostakovich è, a mio avviso, una figura sisifica perchè di
alte ambizioni nella sua origine, viene lanciato in una vita di lunghi
ed incessabili tormenti. Un mondo in cui viene posto davanti all&rsquo;assurda
combinazione di uno spirito creativo e di una censura stringente che gli
tarpa le ali. Di fronte a questa incompatibilità, esplora ogni aspetto
umano della sofferenza, passando dal tentativo di passare attorno alla
censura coi suoi stratagemmi (come nel caso dell&rsquo;Età dell&rsquo;Oro), a
semplicemente nascondere il suo estro sotto ad una maschera di
propaganda, come nella Quinta e nella Settima, a trovare sfogo nella
musica da camera, a grandi atti di ribellione come la Nona, che però
paga cari ogni volta. E quando giunge alla Questione per antonomasia,
trova conforto nella Ribellione, e giunge alla conclusione che la vita
sia degna di essere vissuta. Non penso si possa dire abbia vissuto
propriamente in modo felice, ma trovo che la sua sopravvivenza soltanto
possa rendere innegabile che se una figura mitologica nella ribellione
all&rsquo;assurdo può trovare addirittura felicità, noi come Shostakovich
possiamo sperare di trovare sopportazione.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>TIL that San&#39;Orsola is pretty much the size of a small town</title>
			<link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/sant_orsola/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 18:50:49 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/sant_orsola/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[%!s(<nil>)]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Easter night I had the pleasure to visit the Sant&rsquo;Orsola policlinic&rsquo;s ER. On the way there, I had to cross the entire hostpital&rsquo;s grounds. I must say, they really are impressive. It felt like walking through a campus mixed with a park. Really nice.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>An analysis of the correlation between gun regulation and public safety in the United States of America</title>
			<link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/gun_deaths_paper/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:56:05 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/gun_deaths_paper/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[%!s(<nil>)]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>   <em>Abstract</em>&mdash;
The aim of this paper is to provde a summary analysis of the data regarding the effectiveness of gunrestriction policy in diminishing the numberof gun-related deaths. We do so by conducting an analysis of three different datasets, and by combining the data we gathered from them, and constructing a linear regression model. The constructed linear regression model shows a negative correlation between the gun-related death rate and the amount of legislation present within the state. This suggests that it&rsquo;s possible for legislation to have a positive effect on gun-related deaths.</p>
<h1 id="introduction">Introduction</h1>
<p>The topic of gun regulation has been discussed at length in the United States of America, because of the real and present danger that it poses to Public Safety. There&rsquo;s little doubt that policy has potential to have a substantial effect, and information coming from data analysis can be useful in supporting the decision making. The aim of this paper is to conduct a summmary analysis of the correlation between overall presence of gun restriction and the rate of deaths caused by guns.</p>
<h2 id="paper-overview">Paper overview</h2>
<p>In this paper, we analysed data coming from three different datasets: one is a collection of all gun restiction laws that have been put in place by individual states, the second is a collection of gun deaths by county. The third trakcs violent crime rates.</p>
<p>The scope of the paper is national, and we aim to obtain valuable information by comparing the performance of different states within the same country: we expect the cultural differences to be (even if still present) less impactful than they would be in a inter-country comparison, and thus hope to be able to eliminate most untraceable biases that would arise from it.</p>
<p>To reach our conclusions, we conducted an analysis of the 3 datasets, using them as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>From the first dataset, we extracted an index to answer the question &lsquo;how much regulation around guns is present in this state?&rsquo;</li>
<li>From the second dataset, we extracted aggregated data by year and by state regarding deaths and rates of death by guns.</li>
<li>From the third dataset, we extracted information about the change in violent crime rates over time, to be able to set up a multiple linear regression model.</li>
</ul>
<p>Overall, we found a negative correlation between the gun provision index and the gun death rate, even when accounting for the changes in violent crime.</p>
<h1 id="methods">Methods</h1>
<h2 id="preparing-the-datasets">Preparing the Datasets</h2>
<h3 id="dataset-1">Dataset 1</h3>
<p>The first dataset is comprised of informations regarding deaths by guns divided by county, but our analysis takes place at the state level. Therefore, the dataset was grouped by state and we removed superfluous variables like county code, state code and state initials.</p>
<p>Additionally all of our datasets contain data compiled at different points in time so the information was filtered to retain only the years overlapping across all three datasets, the nineteen years from 1999 to 2017.</p>
<p>The preparation was done in the following way:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">gundeaths_cut</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span> <span class="n">gun_deaths_us_1999_2019[</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="nf">c</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="m">1</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="m">3</span><span class="o">:</span><span class="m">5</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="m">7</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="n">]</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">gundeaths_cut</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span> <span class="nf">subset</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">gundeaths_cut</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="o">!</span><span class="n">gundeaths_cut</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">Year</span> <span class="o">&gt;</span> <span class="m">2017</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">gundeaths_cut</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span> <span class="n">gundeaths_cut[</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="nf">c</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="m">5</span><span class="o">:</span><span class="m">10</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="n">]</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">gundeaths_cond</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span> <span class="n">gundeaths_cut</span> <span class="o">%&gt;%</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="nf">group_by</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nf">across</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nf">where</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">is.character</span><span class="p">)))</span> <span class="o">%&gt;%</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="nf">summarise</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nf">across</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nf">where</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">is.numeric</span><span class="p">),</span> <span class="n">sum</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">na.rm</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="bp">T</span><span class="p">),</span> <span class="n">.groups</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s">&#34;drop&#34;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>We then constructed a simple rate, balanced over 100,000 people, to provide for the different populations between states.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">gundeaths_cond</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">Rate</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span> <span class="m">0</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="kr">for</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i</span> <span class="kr">in</span> <span class="m">1</span><span class="o">:</span><span class="nf">nrow</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">gundeaths_cond</span><span class="p">))</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="n">gundeaths_cond</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">Rate[i]</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span> <span class="p">((</span><span class="n">gundeaths_cond</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">Deaths[i]</span> <span class="o">/</span> <span class="n">gundeaths_cond</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">Population[i]</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">*</span> <span class="m">100000</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="p">}</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>The the final form of the dataset was:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th><strong>Year</strong></th>
<th><strong>State</strong></th>
<th><strong>Deaths</strong></th>
<th><strong>Population</strong></th>
<th><strong>Rate</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1999</td>
<td>Alabama</td>
<td>605</td>
<td>3047241</td>
<td>19.854025</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&hellip;</td>
<td>&hellip;</td>
<td>&hellip;</td>
<td>&hellip;</td>
<td>&hellip;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3 id="dataset-2">Dataset 2</h3>
<p>The second dataset contains all of the laws restricting gun usage for each US state, represented by 133 binary variables.
Aside from filtering for the correct years a Index (referred to as &ldquo;Gun Regulation Index&rdquo; from here on) was constructed usin min-max normalization.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">law_provision_norm</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span> <span class="nf">subset</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">law_provision_norm</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="o">!</span><span class="n">law_provision_norm</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">year</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="m">1999</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">proc_lawprov</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span> <span class="nf">preProcess</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nf">as.data.frame
</span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="nf"></span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">law_provision_norm</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">lawtotal</span><span class="p">),</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">    <span class="n">method</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nf">c</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">&#34;range&#34;</span><span class="p">))</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">law_provision_norm</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">index</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span> <span class="nf">predict</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">proc_lawprov</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nf">as.data.frame</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">law_provision_norm</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">lawtotal</span><span class="p">))</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>To account for differences, states were given scores, &ldquo;Very Low&rdquo; &ldquo;Low&rdquo; &ldquo;Medium&rdquo; &ldquo;High&rdquo;, according to their Gun Regulation Index.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">merged</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">Score</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span> <span class="nf">ifelse</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nf">unlist</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">merged</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">index</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="m">0.25</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s">&#34;Very Low&#34;</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="nf">ifelse</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nf">unlist</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">merged</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">index</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="m">0.5</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s">&#34;Low&#34;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nf">ifelse</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nf">unlist</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">merged</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">index</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="m">0.75</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s">&#34;Medium&#34;</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="s">&#34;High&#34;</span><span class="p">)))</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Final product:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th><strong>Year</strong></th>
<th><strong>State</strong></th>
<th><strong>Law Total</strong></th>
<th><strong>Index</strong></th>
<th><strong>Score</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1999</td>
<td>Alabama</td>
<td>16</td>
<td>0.126213592</td>
<td>Very Low</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&hellip;</td>
<td>&hellip;</td>
<td>&hellip;</td>
<td>&hellip;</td>
<td>&hellip;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3 id="dataset-3">Dataset 3</h3>
<p>The third dataset, mainly added for multiple linear regression purposes in an attempt to account for Omittted Variable Bias, contains the raw numbers of different types of crimes committed in each state. To keep the data as closely related to guns as possible, and to make sure there was no instance of double counting (it wasn&rsquo;t made clear what of the specific crimes listed counted as a &lsquo;Violent Crime&rsquo;) we just included &ldquo;Violent Crimes&rdquo;.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span>  <span class="nf">subset</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">estimated_crimes</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">estimated_crimes</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">year</span> <span class="o">&gt;=</span> <span class="m">1999</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span>  <span class="nf">subset</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">year</span> <span class="o">&lt;=</span> <span class="m">2017</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span>  <span class="nf">subset</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="o">!</span><span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">state_name</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s">&#34;District of Columbia&#34;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span>  <span class="nf">subset</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="o">!</span><span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">state_name</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="s">&#34;&#34;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span> <span class="o">&lt;-</span>  <span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut[</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="nf">c</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="m">2</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="m">4</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="m">6</span><span class="o">:</span><span class="m">15</span><span class="p">)</span><span class="n">]</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>A Violent crime rate was then constructed, balanced on thousands of people.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-r" data-lang="r"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="n">estimatedcrimes_cut</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">VCrime_Rate</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="m">0</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="kr">for</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i</span> <span class="kr">in</span> <span class="m">1</span><span class="o">:</span><span class="nf">nrow</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">expl_merge</span><span class="p">))</span> <span class="p">{</span>
</span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl">  <span class="n">expl_merge</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">VCrime_Rate[i]</span><span class="o">&lt;-</span> <span class="p">((</span><span class="n">expl_merge</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">violent_crime[i]</span> <span class="o">/</span> <span class="n">expl_merge</span><span class="o">$</span><span class="n">Population[i]</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">*</span> <span class="m">1000</span><span class="p">)}</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>The data obtained was formatted in the following way:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th><strong>Year</strong></th>
<th><strong>State</strong></th>
<th><strong>Violent Crimes</strong></th>
<th><strong>VCrime Rate</strong></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1999</td>
<td>Alabama</td>
<td>21421</td>
<td>7.029638</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>&hellip;</td>
<td>&hellip;</td>
<td>&hellip;</td>
<td>&hellip;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="descriptive-analysis">Descriptive Analysis</h2>
<h3 id="dataset-1-1">Dataset 1</h3>
<p>The Gun Deaths dataset shows the average deaths per year to be 515.34, with a standard deviation of 605.09 (this is not a typo, it&rsquo;s a quirk of the average spanning across several years), the death rate instead has an average of 11.90% and a standard deviation of 4.67%, these descriptive statistics, although weak alone, show a variance of considerabe size.</p>
<p><img src="plots/descriptive_plots/Deaths_and_Population.png" alt="imd"></p>
<p><img src="plots/descriptive_plots/Gun_Deaths_and_Population_over_time_(by_year).png" alt="imd"></p>
<p>The graphs show the variance and its evolution over time.</p>
<p>To aid visualization we also constructed a histogram representing the
death count for each state
<img src="plots/descriptive_plots/Deaths_Histogram.png" alt="imd"></p>
<h3 id="dataset-2-1">Dataset 2</h3>
<p>For the law provision dataset the mean of the law total is 24.92, with a
standard deviation of 23.60, instead the mean of the Gun Regualtion
Index is 0.21, with a standard deviation of 0.23, again showing a big
variance in our data.</p>
<p><img src="plots/descriptive_plots/Gun_Regulation_index_in_states.png" alt="imd"></p>
<p>As is easily interpretable, most of the states kept a very low index for the time period analyzed in this study, but there are instances of some states, for example the state of California, keeping very high Index values across the whole time period. This wide gap was not a surprise, as the difference of positions of prominent political figures in the respective states are pretty representative of their -be it high or low- index score.</p>
<p><img src="plots/descriptive_plots/Gun_Regulation_Index_over_time_(by_state).png" alt="imd"></p>
<p>In order to understand the importance of the division of the states in accordance to their scores, it&rsquo;s important to visualize the position of the US states, as the differences will become very apparent.</p>
<p><img src="plots/descriptive_plots/Index_score_count.png" alt="imd"></p>
<p>This bar chart represents the scores of all the US states across our 19 year time period, and it&rsquo;s pretty easy to say that seeing these discrepancies also shaped our future analyisis and prompted us towards conducting it by keeping track at all times of each state&rsquo;s score.</p>
<h3 id="dataset-3-1">Dataset 3</h3>
<p>The third dataset, the one containing the information about violent crimes in the US presents itself in an analogous way to the previous datasets.
The mean of the violent crimes is 26976.7 per year, with a standard deviation of 34431.64 (again, this is also not a typo. See previous footnote), while the mean of the violent crime rate is 6.18%, with a standard deviation of 2.62%</p>
<p>Once again, a high variance is observable across all of our data, again suggesting the importance of a criteria of distinction (in our case the index score) in the state-level analysis to capture efficiently correlations and statistically useful results.</p>
<p><img src="plots/descriptive_plots/Violent_crime_rate_and_population.png" alt="imd">
<img src="plots/descriptive_plots/Violent_crime_rate_over_time_by_state.png" alt="imd"></p>
<h2 id="explorative-analysis">Explorative Analysis</h2>
<p>Having established the nature and characteristics of the three datasets, we now proceed to conduct an analysis of the combination of their data. The aim of this analysis is to establish the impact (or lack there of) of legislation on gun death rates. In order to do so, we first seek to check for the presence of correlation, and then formulate a linear regression model. We then will try to integrate data from possibly correlated variables in an attempt to remove omitted variable bias, and thus create a multiple linear regression model.</p>
<p>The explorative analysis began by plotting and calculating the mean gun death rate (by 100,000) over time, and comparing it with the mean Gun Regulation index over time.
<img src="plots/explorative_plots/Death_rate_vs_Gun_Regulation.png" alt="imd"></p>
<p>At a first glance just by looking at the graphs side to side may lead us to think that even if the Gun Regulation Index has been rising over time the Deaths by guns still don&rsquo;show any signs of decreasing, but a closer inspection reveals that the Gun Regulation Index over nineteen years has only increased by a meager 0.04% and to discern a pattern we need to go deeper and look for substantial causal effects.</p>
<p>By calulating the Pearson correlation between the Gun Regulation Index and the gun death rate we&rsquo;re returned with a value -0.624, suggesting a non-negligible negative correlation between them</p>
<p><img src="plots/explorative_plots/General_gdvsgr.png" alt="imd"></p>
<p>By plotting them in the same graph the negative correlation becomes obvious, but we can also notice the skewedness of observations towards the low values of the Gun Regulation Index, so in accordance to our prior suggestion we split the observations in accordance with their own Index score bracket and run the same analysis.
<img src="plots/explorative_plots/comb_gdvsgr.png" alt="imd">
By splitting the observations we get a clearer image: the -0.624 correlation isn&rsquo;t consistent across all states, but the pattern can still be observed.</p>
<p>The correlations for each groups are as follows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Very low score states = -0.375</li>
<li>Low score states = -0.254</li>
<li>Medium score states = -0.555</li>
<li>High score states = -0.4123633</li>
</ul>
<p>Here we also begin to see the signs of a pattern repeating also in the next steps: Medium score countries tend to have the highest correlation among all of the groups.</p>
<p>Now, after setting up a linear model, we obtained the results of an intercept equal to 14.63 and the index coefficient equal to -12.65.</p>
<p>This number may seem absurdly big, but during the interpretation it is useful to remember that our index is normalised. So, while an increase of 1 would result in very high differences in value, normal increases are in the order of magnitute of 0.1, thus making the data immediately appear more reasonable.</p>
<p>To supplement the current model with regards to the general unreliability and susceptibility to outliers of linear regression, and the possible presence of omitted variable bias, we decided to aid our analysis with the inclusion of the third dataset, with the aim of constructing some additional linear models and useful plots.</p>
<p><img src="plots/explorative_plots/VCR_vs_DR_vs_GR.png" alt="imd">
Before cimenting ourselves into the actual model building, we included the evolution of the mean violent crime rate over time and, once again an immediate analysis may lead us to think that as the Gun Regulation Index increased the violent crime rate decreased, and this is also supported by the correlation between them (-0.293), and their plot.
<img src="plots/explorative_plots/Violent_crime_vs_index_allstates.png" alt="imd">
But we very quickly found out that this plot is actually very misleading, and the analysis on subset of states havin similar score is more interesting.
<img src="plots/explorative_plots/Violent_crime_vs_index_comb.png" alt="imd">
Now that the plots are much clearer, while our pattern in the sheer size of the negative correlation between our values in medium score states is visible to the naked eye, we can also observe some instances of positive correlations in some of the following cases:</p>
<ul>
<li>Very low score states = -0.0596</li>
<li>Low score states =  0.403</li>
<li>Medium score states =  -0.654</li>
<li>High score states = 0.229</li>
</ul>
<p>While the social interpretation of these findings is out of the scope of this study without claiming anythin we can still infer that the data shows that increasing the Gun Regulation Index has some dubious effects in relation with the Violent Crime Rate, we can still interpret that Violent Crime is not a simple enough issue that can be fixed just by increasing Gun Control.</p>
<p>Building a linear model emphasizes this finding since it returned us a value of 6.896 for the intercept and of -3.335 for our Gun Regulation Index.</p>
<p>Now, we may also be interested in the relationship between gun deaths and the violent crime rate, so we calculated once again the correlation between them and obtained a value of 0.471, showing that indeed they are correlated.</p>
<p><img src="plots/explorative_plots/Violent_crime_vs_Gun_death_allstates.png" alt="imd"></p>
<p>Now,to understand relationships on a deeper level, we once again divided the states in accordance to their score.
<img src="plots/explorative_plots/Violent_crimes_vs_gun_deaths_comb.png" alt="imd"></p>
<p>In this case we can observe that all of our brackets contain some level of positive correlation, in particular:</p>
<ul>
<li>Very low score states = 0.371</li>
<li>Low score states =  0.285</li>
<li>Medium score states = 0.685</li>
<li>High  score states = 0.239</li>
</ul>
<p>As anticipated before, medium score states continue to stand out in their high correlations with the studied subjects, but once again the interpretation is out of the scope of this paper.
Some further analysis could lead to the underlying motives of the pattern, maybe trough the identification of some omitted characteristics common to the medium scored countries which point towards this particular outcome, or through the analysis of the immediate effects of increasing the Gun Regulation Index, understanding the mechanisms that shape them in differently scored states.</p>
<p>By building a linear model we&rsquo;re met with the following results:
a value of 3.029 for the intercept and  0.264 for the Death Rate coefficient, showing a surprisingly low coefficient, but understandable, since the Death Rate is balanced over 100.000 people.</p>
<p>For the final passage of our study we culminated the research by trying to draw some conclusions making use of multiple linear regression in an attempt to fix eventual mistakes made with the usage of linear regression, in other words by adding the Violent Crime rate we try to solve some of the omitted variable bias that could have tampered with our data.</p>
<p>With the construction of the Multiple linear regression model we obtained the values of:  10.755 for the intercept,  -10.775 for the coefficient of our Gun Regulation Index and 0.563 for the coefficient of the violent crime rate.</p>
<p>Even if the coefficient of the violent crime rate returned pretty small values, since also the intercept and the coefficient for Gun Regulation got smaller means that we achieved our aim of covering some of the unexplained variance.</p>
<p>We then plot these results in a 3d interactive plot (available for download in the GitHub repository for this study and <a href="https://soliprems.web.app/gd_gr_vc_3dplot.html">here</a>, that due to the limitations of pdfs (and skill issues in the web version) can be relayed here only in the form of an image.
<img src="plots/explorative_plots/gd_gr_vc_plot.png" alt="imd"></p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<h1 id="conclusions">Conclusions</h1>
<p>The relationship that emerges from the data is clear, even if not perfectly consistent: there&rsquo;s a negative correlation between our gun provision index and the gun death rate. This correlation gets weaker with the introduction of violent crime rates as a regressor in the linear regression model, but it remains negative on the whole (although it becomes positive in the case of low and high score states. It&rsquo;s worth noting that they&rsquo;re a much smaller sample than the very low score states, which remains negative. This is visible by the total remaining overall negative).<br>
While the policy analysis is complicated, this would seem to suggest that it&rsquo;s possible, although obviously not guaranteed, to write legislation that aims and achieves and improvement in the number of gun-related deaths.</p>
<h2 id="future-work">Future work</h2>
<p>The work could benefit with an expansion in a few areas:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Integration of more variables that might be correlated with the gun
death rate in order to escapoe possibleomitted variable bias</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>analysis of the effectiveness in relation to the intentionality
behind gun deaths: what kind of deaths does gun control prevent?</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="appendix">Appendix</h1>
<p>The full script and project contents are freely available <a href="https://github.com/soliprem/statistics-project">here</a> under the GPL_v3 license.</p>
<h2 id="contributions">Contributions</h2>
<h3 id="francesco-prem-solidoro">Francesco Prem Solidoro</h3>
<p>Contributed to the writing of the code, to the search and reformatting
of the datasets, to the writing of the document (in particular:
abstract, conclusions) and management of the tooling used for the
project (github, git, typst.app, firebase)</p>
<h3 id="michele-salvi">Michele Salvi</h3>
<p>Contributed to the writing of the code, to the search and reformatting
of the datasets, and to the writing of the document (in particular:
methodology, sections A, B and C)</p>
<h3 id="juan-calani">Juan Calani</h3>
<p>Contributed to the idealization of the project, organization, and provided a reiview of the work.</p>
<h3 id="elena-rocco">Elena Rocco</h3>
<p>Contributed to the idealization of the project, organization, and provided a reiview of the work.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Why</title>
			<link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/why/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 06:10:08 +0100</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/why/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[%!s(<nil>)]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="why-make-a-random-website">Why make a random website?</h1>
<p>Why make a random-ass website? There so many!</p>
<p>I simply don&rsquo;t care. Why do people make social media accounts, if they&rsquo;ve nothing to share? At least as I share my nothing into the void, I stand to learn something. Maybe some new components of hugo. Maybe, who knows, one day I&rsquo;ll rewrite this all into go and htmx. I find intrinsic value in knowing that I likely stand to learn from whatever I&rsquo;m doing at any given time.</p>
<p>The real deal comes in the fact that this is just <em>my</em> space. It&rsquo;s not twitter, instagram, or whatever. It&rsquo;s me, and I have all of the freedom I could dream for to express myself within this website. I feel like social media has a chokehold on both free time and creative expression, and I seek to change it on a personal level by minimizing my engagement with it. So from now on, I&rsquo;ll try to keep it simple, and write things here. <a href="/index.xml">this</a> is an RSS feed you can subscribe to to know when I post new things.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Beeper</title>
			<link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/beeper/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 11:45:22 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/beeper/</guid>
			<description><![CDATA[%!s(<nil>)]]></description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="what-is-beeper">What is Beeper</h1>
<p><a href="https://www.beeper.com">Beeper</a> is a messaging app that seeks to end the issue of fragmentation, by allowing users to use any of 14 currently supported protocols for their chats. These protocols include things like Whatsapp, Telegram, Discord, Slack and many more.<br>
Recently my turn has arrived to access to Beeper&rsquo;s open beta. I&rsquo;ve had a chance to try it out for the past couple of days and I must say, I&rsquo;m impressed.</p>
<p>All Beeper had to do to catch my eye was to promise a convenient way to unify all the different networks that currently dominate the market: this kind of exploitation of platform&rsquo;s network effects is harmful not only to the end consumer, who might not be able to link to all their acquaintances without using 10 different apps. Thankfully I&rsquo;m happy to report that it does much, much more.</p>
<h1 id="beeper-as-a-daily-driver">Beeper as a Daily Driver</h1>
<p>Beeper has some strong competition in the way of chat app clients: from telegram, to element, to discord, there&rsquo;s many affirmed workflows that open it up from nitpicking from each of the communities it&rsquo;s trying to appeal to.</p>
<p>As an example, a telegram user using the mobile app might miss some of the gesture navigation controls to open the side menu, and find the single swipe to archive clumsy. On the other hand, a google messages user will feel right at home with with this default.<br>
In other words, Beeper is definitely facing  a major UX challenge, but from what I&rsquo;ve had the chance to experience so far, I&rsquo;d say they&rsquo;re rising to it.</p>
<h1 id="interesting-positives">Interesting Positives</h1>
<p>Other than the headline feature, the support for many different chat protocols, there&rsquo;s a few interesting positive notes:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Beeper&rsquo;s Support:</strong> One of the more surprising experiences while using beeper was the close relationship users have with support. Given this is a preview, it&rsquo;s not unexpected for the Beeper to expect feedback, but the way they integrated it is very fascinating: simply put, you get a <a href="/img/beeper.png">chat with support</a> integrated into the app. This makes the experience more personal, and the response times very short.</li>
<li><strong>Vim-like Navigation:</strong> simply put, the desktop app seems to have some modal-like workflow, which I find very intuitive: pressing esc will shift the focus from the chat to the navigator, allowing for j and k to be used to move up and down, other than the arrow keys. All keybinds are easily accessible in the settings window, or by pressing <code>ctrl+/</code>.</li>
<li><strong>Theming:</strong> the application allows for costum CSS theming. For examples or to suggest new themes, visit the <a href="https://github.com/beeper/themes">github repo</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="closing-thoughts">Closing Thoughts</h1>
<p>Overall, I have no major gripes with the application. While there&rsquo;s no plans to integrate discord/slack voice chat in the app, that was expected, as it&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/beeper/comments/13rv6kt/comment/jlql09e/?context=3">not aiming for feature parity with every client whose protocol it supports</a>, but it&rsquo;s trying to be, simply put, <strong>the best messaging app possible</strong>. Personally, I believe the way forward is to keep refining the experience by keeping up with fixing the bugs that they are so incredibly open to receive feedback on, and working on customization options, such as the gesture navigation mentioned above.</p>
<p>Until then, I&rsquo;ll still be using Beeper as my main messaging app, even if I still have to switch back to answer polls and use stickers, or send single-view pictures. The experience of having every chat in the same place, being able to navigate quickly with vim-like keybinds in the desktop app (don&rsquo;t worry, it&rsquo;s not the only option. You can still use the mouse or the arrows), and the excellent search implementation make it all around enjoyable to use.</p>
<h2 id="learn-more">Learn More</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://beeper.com">beeper&rsquo;s official site</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/beeper/comments/13rv6kt/beeper_ceo_ama_may_26_2023_noon_pdt/?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;context=3">last official Reddit AMA</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
